Nevada Folklife Archive
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 3: Photographs
  - Subseries 2: Negatives, 620 still images (.jpg); 620 still images (.tif)
    - Navrati (Gujurati East Indian nine day festival honoring Durga) Celebration at Sierra Arts Foundation, October 8, 1994, AFC 2017/002: P-1994-016; Eliza Buck; 25 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 8)
    - Navrati Festival, Gujurati East Indian, Bethel AME (African Methodist Episcopal) Church, Sparks, October 8, 1994, AFC 2017/002: P-1994-017; Eliza Buck; 25 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 8)
    - H.B. McCay, farrier, shoeing horse in Lemmon Valley, October 10, 1994, AFC 2017/002: P-1994-018; Eliza Buck; 22 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 8)
    - Tongan children of First United Methodist Congregation hold dance and choir practice at lay minister's home in Sparks, October 10, 1994, AFC 2017/002: P-1994-019; Eliza Buck; 24 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 8)
    - Tongan children, First United Methodist Congregation, dance and choir practice at lay minister's home in Sparks; Colin Sendall, dowsing (16-21): Mexican folklorico (22-25), October 2, 1994, AFC 2017/002: P-1994-020; Eliza Buck; 25 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 8)
    - Mexican folklorico dance(3-14); Arun Sachdev site visit (15-25), October 13, 1994, AFC 2017/002: P-1994-021; Eliza Buck; 25 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 8)
    - Arun Sachdev site visit (1); Karen Burns site visit (2-6); Nancy and Crystal Jackson demonstrate African-American hairdos (7-24), October 14, 1994, AFC 2017/002: P-1994-022; Eliza Buck; 24 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 8)
    - Norm DeLorme and traditional Paiute basketry (1-8); The Steeles - Circus trapeze flyers practicing in their front yard (9-17), Lawrence Lopes yard art in his front yard (18-25), October 15, 1994, AFC 2017/002: P-1994-023; Eliza Buck; 25 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 8)
    - Labor Day Rodeo, Owyhee (3-14); Reno Greek Festival (15-25), September 4, 1994, AFC 2017/002: P-1994-024; Andrea Graham; 25 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 8)
    - Reno Greek Festival (2-15); FAA 1994, Oscar Carrescia (master) and Olga Carbia (apprentice, Argentinean guitar) (16-22); FAA 1994, Pysanky, Zoria Zetaruk (master), Natalie Pruc, Luba Eads (apprentices) (23-24), September 10, 1994, AFC 2017/002: P-1994-025; Andrea Graham; 24 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 8)
    - FAA 1995 rehearsal for Kaminari Taiko Drummers. Doug Muraoka (master), William Fujii and Norma Honda Wagoner (apprentices), September 21, 1994, AFC 2017/002: P-1994-026; Andrea Graham; 24 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 8)
    - FAA 1995, saddle making, Alan McDonald (apprentice) Eddie Brooks (master) (2-6); FAA 1995, African drumming, Eric Jackson (apprentice) African drumming Mohamed Barrie (master) (7-20), September 28, 1994, AFC 2017/002: P-1994-027; Andrea Graham; 20 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 8)
    - Taiko and African drumming exchange (1-16); Virginia McCuin, silversmith (17-24), November 16, 1994, AFC 2017/002: P-1994-028; Andrea Graham; 24 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 8)
    - Annual mochi-making party of Reno Japanese American Food Citizen's League, November 20, 1994, AFC 2017/002: P-1994-029 - P-1994-030; Andrea Graham; 48 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 8)
    - FAA 1995 buckskin, Lyle Sam, Ed McDade (1-9); FAA 1995 saddle making, Eddie Brooks master, Alan McDonald apprentice (10-16), Cowboy Poetry Gathering, NAM cooking demo, Lois Whitney and Elizabeth Brady (17-24), January 1995, AFC 2017/002: P-1995-001; Andrea Graham; 24 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 8)
    - FAA 1995 apprenticeship, Shoshone basketry. Virginia Sanchez (on sofa) working on a small cone basket at her mother Lilly's (standing) house. Baby is Virginia's daughter Cora, January 14, 1995, AFC 2017/002: P-1995-002; Andrea Graham; 24 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 8)
    - Cowboy Poetry Gathering, NAM cooking demo, Lois Whitney and Elizabeth Brady (3-7); Las Vegas Folklife Festival - school program (8-25), 1995, AFC 2017/002: P-1995-003; Andrea Graham; 24 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 8)
    - Las Vegas Folklife Festival, April 21, 995, AFC 2017/002: P-1995-004 - P-1995-009; Andrea Graham; 155 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 8)
    - Sierra Folklife Festival, July 29, 1995, AFC 2017/002: P-1995-010 - P-1995-014; Andrea Graham; 123 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 8)
    - Sierra Folklife Festival; (3-4), FAA 1995-1996, Mexican Ballet Folklorico, Icela Gutierrez and Gabriela Tschudy, Las Vegas (5-18); FAA 1995-1996, Amy Rovere, master (19-25), 1995, AFC 2017/002: P-1995-015; Andrea Graham; 24 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 8)
    - FAA 1995-1996, Amy Rovere, master (1-6); FAA 1995-1996 Thai dance, master Wanthanee Natechoei, Panee Connoly apprentice (7-16), September 21, 1995, AFC 2017/002: P-1995-016; Andrea Graham; 24 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 8)
    - FAA 1995-1996 Thai dance, master Wanthanee Natechoei, Panee Connoly apprentice (2-15); FAA 1995-1996 Senegalese dance, Malick Sow master, Abayomi Goodall apprentice (16-25), October 1995, AFC 2017/002: P-1995-017; Andrea Graham; 25 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 8)
    - FAA 1995-1996 Senegalese dance, Malick Sow master, Abayomi Goodall apprentice, October 26, 1995, AFC 2017/002: P-1995-018; Andrea Graham; 23 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 8)
    - FAA 1995-1996, Washoe acorn biscuits, Madelina Henry, November 28, 1995, AFC 2017/002: P-1995-019; Andrea Graham; 25 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 8)
    - FAA 1995-1996, December 10, 1995, AFC 2017/002: P-1995-020; Andrea Graham; 23 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 8)
    - Las Vegas Folklife Festival, 1995, AFC 2017/002: P-1995-021; Andrea Graham; 24 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 8)
    - Sierra Folklife Festival, 1995, AFC 2017/002: P-1995-022; Susan Boskoff; 19 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 8)
    - FAA 1995-1996 apprenticeship in rawhide braiding, master, Randy Stowell (in plaid shirt), apprentice, Hank Brackenbury (in vest), March 9, 1996, AFC 2017/002: P-1996-001 - P-1996-002; Andrea Graham; 49 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - FAA 1995-1996, Randy Stowell - Master (plaid shirt), Hank Brackenbury - Apprentice (vest) (0-13); FAA 1995-1996 Mexican Vivo dance group. Master Icela Gutierrez not present (14-24), March 9, 1996, AFC 2017/002: P-1996-003; Andrea Graham; 16 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - FAA 1995-1996 Performance by Philippine Dance Company of Nevada at Christ Lutheran Church, Las Vegas. Group taught by Amy Rovere, FAA master, and including apprentice Kim Arche, March 30, 1996, AFC 2017/002: P-1996-004; Andrea Graham; 24 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - FAA 1995-1996 Performance by Philippine Dance Company of Nevada at Christ Lutheran Church, Las Vegas. (3-9); Las Vegas Folklife Festival - school festival at Lorenzi Park (10-25), March 30, 1996, AFC 2017/002: P-1996-005; Andrea Graham; 25 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - Las Vegas Folklife Festival, April 25, 1996, AFC 2017/002: P-1996-006 - P-1996-008; Andrea Graham; 73 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - Las Vegas Folklife Festival, FAA 1995-1996, April 26, 1996, AFC 2017/002: P-1996-009; Andrea Graham; 23 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - Las Vegas Folklife Festival, April 27, 1996, AFC 2017/002: P-1996-010 - P-1996-016; Andrea Graham; 75 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - Arts All Ways Conference in Las Vegas (6-24), September 14, 1996, AFC 2017/002: P-1996-017; Andrea Graham; 12 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - Arts All Ways Conference in Las Vegas (9-17); Ida Mae Valdez, expedition in Smith Valley to locate traditional plants with Lillius Richardson, Marlin Thompson, Nicholas Curchin Vrooman, Smith Valley (18-25), October 1996, AFC 2017/002: P-1996-018; Andrea Graham; 24 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - FAA 1996-1997, Melanie Bryan, Jeanne O'Daye with Head Start kids from Hungry Valley on picnic, also Jean McNicoll (1-6), November 13, 1996, AFC 2017/002: P-1996-019; Andrea Graham; 24 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - [Dooby Avenue folk art environment], August 1996, AFC 2017/002: P-1996-020; Andrea Graham; 14 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - FAA 1997 apprenticeship in traditional plants and medicine, Lillius Richardson, IdaMae Valdez, Marlin Thompson; FAA 1997, Sho-Pai dress making, Harriet Allen, Francine Tohannie, February 10, 1997, AFC 2017/002: P-1997-001; Andrea Graham; 21 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - FAA 1997 Las Vegas Pipe Band rehearsal. John Massie and Wes Hallam; Chanter practice, March 10, 1997, AFC 2017/002: P-1997-002 - P-1997-003; Andrea Graham; 37 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - FAA 1997, Jean McNicoll and Jeanne O'Daye, (taken in Carson City) (2-7); FAA 1997, Norma Smokey and Colleen Hernandez, Washoe basketry, Colleen Hernandez works on winnowing tray (11-25), April 21, 1997, AFC 2017/002: P-1997-004; Andrea Graham; 25 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - FAA 1997, Paiute cradleboard apprenticeship,, May 24, 1997, AFC 2017/002: P-1997-005; Andrea Graham; 25 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - FAA 1997, Lyn Perry Filipino Rondalla (1-7); Las Vegas Community Roots at Rafael Riviera, and interviewing Joe Walker (8-10), August 1997, AFC 2017/002: P-1997-006; Eliza Buck; 24 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - Community Roots, Wells, August 20, 1997, AFC 2017/002: P-1997-007; Eliza Buck; 24 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - Las Vegas Folklife Festival, Lorenzi Park, October 23, 1997, AFC 2017/002: P-1997-008; Eliza Buck; 16 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - Community Roots interview at Luis Manuel's (Mexican singer, folklorist) with Icela Gutierrez, Luis, Mattie Martin, Irma Wynants, Patricia Davis (0-8); Las Vegas Folklife Festival, Lorenzi Park (9-25), Septeber 24, 1997, AFC 2017/002: P-1997-009; Eliza Buck; 25 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - Las Vegas Folklife Festival, October 24, 1997, AFC 2017/002: P-1997-010 - P-1997-011; Andrea Graham; 43 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - Sierra Folklife Festival, September 13, 1997, AFC 2017/002: P-1997-012 - P-1997-017; Andrea Graham; 144 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - Arts Town meetings (1-9); shoe tree (10-14); FAA 1998 John Massie, Wes Hallam (15-23), February 1998, AFC 2017/002: P-1998-001; Andrea Graham; 23 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - Community Roots workshop (4-23), April 6, 1998, AFC 2017/002: P-1998-002; Eliza Buck; 23 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - FAA 1998, Barbara Lierly, Polish papercutting (1-10); FAA 1998, Filipino Rondalla, Lyn Perry (master), Gloria Fosgate, Katrina Opena (apprentices) (11-21); FAA 1998 Leah Brady (master), Marian Sam (apprentice), (22-25), February 18, 1998, AFC 2017/002: P-1998-003; Andrea Graham; 25 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - FAA 1998, Leah Brady (master), Marian Sam (apprentice), Elko (1-3), FAA 1998, Donald Ike Hicks buckskin tanning at his home in Fallon (4-25), April 10, 1998, AFC 2017/002: P-1998-004; Andrea Graham; 25 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - Community Roots interview with Helen Toland by Community Roots project members, March 1998, AFC 2017/002: P-1998-005; Eliza Buck; 24 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - FAA 1998 apprenticeship in buckskin tanning, with Wesley Dick (master) and Donald Ike Hicks (apprentice), April 10, 1998, AFC 2017/002: P-1998-006; Andrea Graham; 8 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - FAA 1998 willow round baskets. Bernie DeLorme (master), Linda Comas (apprentice). In Bernie's back yard at Reno-Sparks Indian Colony (1-22); Sierra Folklife Festival, Wingfield Park, Reno (23-37), August 8, 1998, AFC 2017/002: P-1998-007; Andrea Graham; 37 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - Sierra Folklife Festival, September 12, 1988, AFC 2017/002: P-1998-008 - P-1998-010; Andrea Graham; 74 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - Sierra Folklife Festival (1); Las Vegas Folklife Festival (2-25), September 12, 1988, AFC 2017/002: P-1998-011; Andrea Graham; 25 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - Las Vegas Folklife Festival - kids day, October 2, 1998, AFC 2017/002: P-1998-012 - P-1998-013; Andrea Graham; 35 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - Las Vegas Folklife Festival (1-12); Arts All Ways (AAW) III (13-15); Community Roots displays in Wells (16-23), October 3, 1998, AFC 2017/002: P-1998-014; Andrea Graham; 23 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - Great Basin Tribal Gathering at the South Fork Reservation. Darlene Dewey (33-35), July 9, 1998, AFC 2017/002: P-1998-016 - P-1998-018; Andrea Graham; 96 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - Performances and demos at Nevada State Museum in conjunction with Handed Down exhibit, August 28, 1999, AFC 2017/002: P-1999-001 - P-1999-003; Andrea Graham; 69 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - Sierra Folklife Festival, September 18, 1999, AFC 2017/002: P-1999-004 - P-1999-005; Andrea Graham; 74 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - Las Vegas Folklife Festival, Children's Day, October 1, 1999, AFC 2017/002: P-1999-006 - P-1999-010; Jeanne Harrah Johnson; 159 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - Nevada Day (1-6); Doug Groves (master) and Grant Groves (apprentice) rawhide braiding apprenticeship, TS Ranch, near Battle Mountain (7-29), October 30, 1999, AFC 2017/002: P-2000-001; Andrea Graham; 29 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
    - Folklife Apprenticeship projects, June 23, 2000, AFC 2017/002: P-2000-002; Andrea Graham; 37 black-and-white film negatives (35mm) (Box 116)
  - Subseries 3: Prints, 427 still images (.jpg); 428 still images (.tif)
    Scope and content: Black-and-white contact sheets from negatives. Also includes color prints of a quilting retreat with no associated negatives.
    Arrangement: This subseries is arranged chronologically. Contact sheets have been linked to their original negatives wherever possible.
    - Black-and-white contact sheets (35mm), 1986-1987, See negatives P-1986-001 - P-1987-028 for detailed description.; 85 black-and-white contact sheets (Box 3)
    - Black-and-white contact sheets (35mm), 1987-1990, See negatives P-1987-101 - P-1990-008 for detailed description.; 140 black-and-white contact sheets (Box 4)
    - Black-and-white contact sheets (35mm), 1991-1995, See negatives P-1991-001 - P-1995-022 for detailed description.; 122 black-and-white contact sheets (Box 5)
    - Black-and-white contact sheets (35mm), 1996-1998, See negatives P-1996-001 - P-1998-016 for detailed description.; 52 black-and-white contact sheets (Box 1)
    - Black-and-white contact sheets (35mm), 1998-2000, See negatives P-1998-017 - P-2000-002 for detailed description.; 14 black-and-white contact sheets (Box 2)
    - Dottie Montgomery's quilting retreat in Tahoe Paradise, California (Meyers), May 31, 2003, AFC 2017/002: P-2003-001; Andrea Graham; 26 color prints (4x6) (Box 2)
  - Subseries 4: Born-digital photographs
    Scope and content: Digital photographs from the beginning of the Nevada Folklife Archive's transition from analog to digital photography.
    - White Pine County cultural survey, 2001, afc2017002_series3_part1; Andrea Graham; D-2001-001; 168 still images (.jpg)
    - White Pine County cultural survey, 2002, afc2017002_series3_part1; Andrea Graham; D-2002-001; 100 still images (.jpg)
    - White Pine County cultural survey, 2002, afc2017002_series3_part1; Andrea Graham; D-2002-002; 46 still images (.jpg)
    - Elaine Smokey and Norberta Whistler, 2003, afc2017002_series3_part1; Jeanne Johnson; D-2003-001; 24 still images (.jpg)
    - Yoko Fitzpatrick, 2005, afc2017002_series3_part1; Anne F. Hatch; D-2005-001; 22 still images (.jpg)